[音乐] 在本节中，我们将介绍
[Music]
in this section we're going to cover two routing algorithms that are widely used
实践中广泛使用的两种路由算法
在今天的互联网中计算从给定源到给定的路径
in practice in today's internet for computing a path from a given source to
目的地第一个被称为链接状态
a given destination the first is known as a link state algorithm the second
算法第二种称为距离向量算法
is known as a distance vector algorithm
尽管他们拥有相同的计算目标
and although they share the same common
goal of computing
最短路径或至少成本路径我们将看到它们不同
shortest path or at least cost path what
we'll see is they differ
非常像他们实际计算这些最短路径的方式
very much in the way in which they
actually compute these shortest paths
任何路由算法的目标都是确定一个好的
the goal of any routing algorithm is to
determine a good
源节点之间的路径或良好的路由或良好的路由
path or a good route or a good route
between a source node
以及通过路由器网络的目标节点
and a destination node through a network
of routers
要理解路由算法，我们需要解压该语句 a
to understand routing algorithms we're
going to need to unpack that statement a
一点点我们所说的路径是什么意思什么是路径
little bit
what do we mean by a path what is a path
通过路由器网络以及良好的含义是什么
through a network of routers
and also what does it mean to be good
一个根好或一个根比另一个好是什么意思
what does it mean for a root to be good
or one root to be better than another
root 所以让我们定义一个路径作为一个序列
root
so let's define a path as a sequence of
数据包从给定的初始源主机经过的路由器
routers that packets traverse
from a given initial source host to the
最终目标主机我们在这里看到来自此源主机的路径
final destination host
we see a path here from this source host
在这个目标主机的左边，在右下角
on the left to this destination host on
the bottom right
通过这五个路由器并隐含在一个路径中是一个序列
passing through these five routers and
implicit in a path being a sequence of
路由器是连接的链接序列
routers
is the sequence of links connecting the
路径中的路由器这些链接将很重要，因为
routers in the path
these links are going to be important as
我们将在一秒钟内看到我们所说的好是什么意思
we'll see in just a sec
and what do we mean by good well could
意味着很多不同的事情也许这是成本最低的路径也许
mean a lot of different things
maybe it's the least cost path maybe
这是最快的路径，也许是最不拥挤的路径，因为
it's the fastest path
maybe it's the least congested path as
我们将看到成本的定义和商品的定义
we'll see the definition of cost and the
definition of good
将留给网络运营商
is going to be left up to the network
operator
在我们深入研究路由算法之前，让我在这里添加
and let me add here before we dive into
routing algorithms that routing is
绝对是 10 大网络挑战，我们将使用图形抽象一个概念
definitely a top 10 networking challenge
we'll use a graph abstraction a concept
这对任何本科计算机科学来说都很熟悉
that's familiar to
any undergraduate computer science
学生已修读数据结构课程或算法课程
student has taken a data structures
course or an algorithms course
来描述一个路由算法，所以一个图由一组
to describe a routing algorithm so a
graph consists of a set of
n 个节点，这些节点可能对应于网络中的路由器
n nodes these might correspond to the
routers within the network
这些端节点通过边或
these end nodes are connected by edges
or
链接，每个链接都有相关的成本
links and each of these links has an
associated cost
节点 a 和 b 之间的链路成本用 c 表示
the link cost between nodes a and b
denoted c
sub ab 是直接链路连接的成本
sub a b is the cost of the direct link
connecting
a 和 b 例如链接 w 之间的成本
a and b for example the cost between
links w
z 在这里表示为 c sub wz 是 x 和 y 之间的成本的五
and z here denoted c sub w z is
five the cost between x and y for this
链接成本是一个链接成本可以
link
the cost is one link costs can be
在每个方向上不同或在这种情况下与此处相同
different in each direction or be the
same as in this case here
最后，不直接连接的两个节点之间的链接成本是
and lastly the link costs between two
nodes that are not directly connected is
将是无穷大例如你和之间的链接成本
going to be infinity
for example the link cost between u and
不直接连接的 z 现在是无穷大，这些成本在哪里
z which are not directly connected
is infinity now where do these costs
来自路由算法或协议
come from
well the routing algorithm or protocol
并不真正关心，但实际上它是由
doesn't really care
but in practice it's defined by the
网络运营商的成本可能是一个，在这种情况下
network operator
the cost could be one in which case the
租赁成本路径算法是最短路径
lease cost path algorithm is the
shortest path
或者成本可能与带宽成反比，越高
or the cost could be inversely related
to the bandwidth the higher the
带宽成本越低或成本可能直接相关
bandwidth the lower the cost
or the cost could be directly related to
一个链接的拥塞程度他们的排队延迟
a link's congestion level their queuing
delay
拥塞程度越高，成本越高
the higher the congestion level the
higher the cost
我们将在一秒钟内查看两种路由算法
we're going to look at two routing
algorithms in just a second
但从广义上讲，我们可以将路由算法分类为任何路由算法
but broadly we can classify routing
algorithms any routing algorithm
根据它们是全球性的还是去中心化的
according to whether
they're global or decentralized and
无论它们在全局算法中是静态的还是动态的
whether they're static or
dynamic in a global algorithm the
算法具有完整的全网信息
algorithm has
complete network-wide information about
网络拓扑和所有链路成本算法与全局
network topology and
all link costs algorithms with global
有时会提到状态信息
state information are sometimes referred
to
作为链接状态算法，因为算法必须知道
as link state algorithms since the
algorithm has to be aware
网络中每个链接的成本
the cost of each and every link in the
network
dijkstra 算法是全局链接状态算法的一个例子
dijkstra's algorithm is an example of a
global link state algorithm
在分布式或分散式路由算法中，计算
in a distributed or decentralized
routing algorithm the calculation of the
泄漏成本路径以迭代方式进行
leaks cost
path is carried out in an iterative
路由器的分布式方式没有路由器有完整的信息
distributed manner by the routers
no router has complete information about
所有网络链接的成本，而不是每个路由器都以
the costs of all network links
instead each router begins with the
知道自己直接附加链接的成本，所以只是它的
knowledge of the cost of its own
directly attached links so just its
局部邻域，然后通过迭代过程
local neighborhood
and then through an iterative process of
计算和交换信息
calculation
and exchange of information with its
直接相邻的节点一个节点迭代计算最少的
immediately neighboring nodes
a node iteratively calculates the least
贝尔曼福特算法将研究的一组目的地的成本路径是
cost path to a set of destinations
the bellman ford algorithm will study is
分布式算法的一个例子，也称为距离向量
an example of a distributed algorithm
also known as a distance vector
算法，因为它迭代计算一个向量
algorithm since it
iteratively computes a vector of
当前已知的所有网络节点的最低成本
currently known least cost to all
network nodes
路由算法也可以归类为静态
routing algorithms can also be
classified as static
或基于时间的动态或准静态
or dynamic or quasi-static based on the
time
他们操作和迭代的规模我们现在准备好看看
scale at which they operate and iterate
we're now ready to take a look at
dijkstra 的链接状态路由算法，我知道你是
dijkstra's link state
routing algorithm and i know if you're a
参加过像 compsci 311 这样的算法课程的学生
student who's taken an algorithms course
like compsci 311
在马萨诸塞大学，你知道你见过迪杰斯特拉的
here at the university of massachusetts
you know you've seen dijkstra's
知道算法不是很好
algorithm
isn't it great to know that the
你在理论课程中学到的算法实际上被用于
algorithm that you learned in a theory
course is actually being used in
实践几乎可以保证你
practice
can almost guarantee you that the
现在作为此视频的一部分传输给您的数据包
packets that are being transferred to
you now as part of this video
几乎可以肯定是使用 dijkstra 的链接状态路由路由给您的
were almost certainly routed to you
using dijkstra's link state routing
algorithm dykstra 的链路状态路由算法
algorithm
dykstra's link state routing algorithm
是一种集中式算法，因为它假设完整的
is a centralized algorithm
because it assumes that the complete
网络拓扑结构和网络中的所有链路开销为
network topology
and all the link costs in the network is
进行计算的节点已知
known to the node that's making the
calculation
算法本身将计算成本最低的路径
the algorithm itself is going to compute
the least cost paths from
一个节点，我们将其称为网络中所有其他节点的源节点
one node which we'll call the source
node to all other nodes in the network
你可以看到这是如何产生转发表的
and you can see how this then gives rise
to a forwarding table
对于那个节点，dijkstra 的算法有一个非常好的属性，它是迭代的
for that node dijkstra's algorithm has
this very nice property it's iterative
在 k 次迭代之后，我们将知道
and
after k iterations we're going to know
到最近或最低成本 k 的最低成本路径
the least cost
path to the closest or least cost k
目的地，这是我们将要使用的符号
destinations and here's a notation that
we're going to use
我们让 c sub ab 是节点 a 之间的直接链接成本
we'll let c sub a b be the direct link
cost between nodes a
和 b 如果节点 a 和 b 没有连接这个成本将是无穷大所以
and b if nodes a and b aren't connected
this cost is going to be infinity so
这只是两个直接之间的一跳直接链接成本
it's just the one hop
direct link cost between two directly
附加节点 d sub a 是当前的估计
attached nodes
d sub a is the current estimate of the
来自源的最小成本路径的成本
cost
of the least cost path from the source
到目的地 a 我们将看到 d sub a 将是
to destination a
as we'll see d sub a is going to be
对所有目的地 a 迭代更新，因为算法先于 p sub a 是
iteratively updated for all destinations
a as the algorithm precedes p sub a is
所谓的前驱节点沿
what's
called the predecessor node along the
从源到节点 a 的路径，最后 n 个素数是节点的集合
path from the source to node a
and finally n prime is the set of nodes
其最低成本路径此时肯定是已知的
whose least cost
path is definitely known at this point
在计算中 现在让我们看一下伪代码
in the calculation
now let's take a look at the pseudo code
用于 dijkstra 的链路状态路由算法
for dijkstra's link state routing
algorithm
最简单的部分是初始化我们要做的就是我们要
the easy part is the initialization what
we're going to do is we're going to
初始化 n 个素数 记住 n 个素数是一组
initialize
n prime remember n prime is the set of
从源节点 u 已知其最低成本路径的节点
nodes whose least cost paths are known
from the source node u
我们将初始化 n 个素数以只包含源节点 u
we're going to initialize n prime to
just contain the source node u
并且对于网络中的所有其他节点 a 并且如果 a 直接连接到
and for all other nodes a within the
network and if a is directly attached to
你然后 d sub a 将等于
u
then d sub a is going to just equal that
一跳花费了从节点 u 到节点 a 的成本，否则
one hop
cost the cost from node u to a otherwise
d sub a 将是无穷大，这很容易初始化
d sub a is going to be infinity
okay that's the initialization easy
足够多的第 8 步到第 15 步是
enough steps
8 through 15 are the heart of the
算法，这只是一个循环我们将在循环中做的事情
algorithm and this is just a loop
what we're going to be doing in the loop
每次我们要找到一个节点 a 我们要把它添加到 n
each time we're going to find
one node a we're going to add it to n
prime，我们将进行更新，然后
prime
and we're going to do an update and then
我们将再次迭代，所以这个循环基本上
we're going to iterate
back again so this loop has basically
两部分找到一个节点，然后执行一个
two parts finding a node and then
performing an
更新让我们现在在第 9 步和第 10 步中查看它
update let's take a look at it now in
steps 9 and 10
我们正在找到一个不在 n 质数中的节点 a 所以这是一个节点
we're finding a node a that's not in n
prime so this is a node
其最低成本路径尚不确定
whose least cost path is not
definitively known
我们会发现 a 不在 m 质数中，使得 d
and we'll find the a not in m prime such
that d
sub a 是最小值，然后我们将它添加到 n 个素数
sub a is a minimum and then we're going
to add it to n prime
请记住，一旦节点添加到 n 个素数，它就永远存在，因为我们
remember once the node's added to n
prime it's in there for good because we
绝对知道到达 a 的最短路径，这就是标识
absolutely know the shortest path
to get to a so that's the identification
循环中的步骤，然后我们有一个更新步骤
step within the loop
and then we've got an update step which
我们在步骤 11 和 12 中看到这里。所以更新步骤如下
we see here in steps 11 and 12.
so the update step is the following
我们将为网络中的所有节点更新 d sub b  紧挨着，也就是说相邻
we're going to update
d sub b for all nodes in the network
我们将为网络中的所有节点更新 d sub b  紧挨着，也就是说相邻
b that are next to that is to say
adjacent
直接连接到 a 并且尚未在 n 质数中，这是我们的更新步骤
directly connected to a and not yet in  prime and here's the update step we're
n prime and here's the update step we're
要说 d sub b 等于
going to say d sub b is equal to the minimum well of the
d sub b 的旧值和潜在的新值会花费新值
old value of d sub b and a potential new cost the new potential
潜在成本是获得记忆的最低成本
cost is the minimum cost to get to a remember this is now known
这是现在已知的加上从 a 到 b 的单跳成本
plus the one hop cost to get from a to b
一旦我们对所有节点 b 执行此更新步骤
once we perform this update step for all
nodes b
与我们循环返回的相邻，我们会找到一个新的
that are adjacent to a we loop back and
we'll find a new
a 所以我们在第八步重新开始
a and so we start off again at step
eight
我们继续这个循环过程添加一个节点
and we continue this looping process
adding one node
每次 a 变成 n 个素数，直到网络中的所有节点都在 n 中
a into n prime each time until
all the nodes in the network are in n
素数可能是最简单的理解方式
prime
probably the easiest way to understand
dijkstra 的算法是看一个
dijkstra's algorithm is to take a look
at an
示例所以让我们接下来做，所以在左下角你可以看到网络
example so let's do that next so on the
bottom left here you see the network on
我们要运行 dijkstra 算法
which
we want to run dijkstra's algorithm
有六个节点和此处显示的链接以及相关链接
there are six nodes and the links shown
here along with the associated link
花费我们要去的源节点
costs
the source node from which we're going
计算所有成本最低的路径是此处最左侧的节点 u
to be computing all the least cost paths
is node u on the far left hand side here
好吧，让我们从初始化步骤开始，因为那是
well let's start off with the
initialization step since that's the
最简单的记住初始化步骤说
easiest
remember the initialization step says
对于所有节点 a 如果 a 与此源节点 u 相邻
for all nodes a
if a is adjacent to this source node u
那么 d sub a 就等于成本
then d sub a is equal simply to the cost
the one
从 u 到 a 的跳直接链接成本，所以让我们看看这里
hop direct link cost of getting from u
to a and so let's take a look here we
可以在这里看到节点 u 的直接邻居
can see here that the direct neighbors
of nodes u
是 vw 和 x 所以你可以在第一行看到到达 v 的成本
are v w and x and so you can see on the
first line here the cost to get to v
是 2 到达 w 的成本 到达 w 的直接成本
is 2 cost to get to w the direct cost to
get to w
是 5，到达 x 的直接成本是 1。我们已经填写了
is 5 and the direct cost to get to x
is 1. and we've filled in the
前驱节点简单地说就是节点vw的前驱
predecessor node simply to say
that the predecessor to nodes v w
和 x 距离 u 的最短路径实际上是节点 u 本身节点 y 和 z
and x the shortest path from u
is actually node u itself nodes y and z
初始化为无穷大，因为它们没有直接的单跳连接
are initialized to infinity because they
don't have a direct one hop connection
源节点 u 所以现在是时候进入我们的
to source node u
and so now it's time to jump into our
首先通过循环步骤 8 9 和 10. 以及步骤 9 和 10
first pass through the loop
steps 8 9 and 10. and in steps 9 and 10
我们要做一个节点识别我们要找到的节点a
we're going to do a node identification
we want to find the node a
还不是 n 个素数，使得 d sub a 到 a 的成本是 a
that's not yet in n prime such that
d sub a the distance the cost to a is a
最小值，然后我们要将 a 添加到 n
minimum
and then we're going to add a into n
素数 所以看看上面的表格，我们看到 b 的成本是 2 成本
prime so taking a look at the table
above we see the cost of b is 2 the cost
w 为 5 时 x 的成本为 1。
of w
is 5 the cost to x is 1.
所以 x 是我们要添加节点的最小值
so x is the minimum here we're going to
add node
x 变成 n 个素数，你可以在我们绘制的图表的左下角看到
x into n prime and you can see on the
bottom left here on the graph we've
画了一个红色的小箭头来表示从 u 到 x
drawn a little red arrow to show that to
get from u to x
这是一个直接连接，现在让我们继续更新步骤，然后
that's a direct connection there now
let's proceed on to the update step and
这在此处的步骤 11 中显示，我们将更新 dcb 的方式是
this is shown in step 11 here
and the way we're going to update dcb is
此处显示 d sub b 的新值将是
shown here
the new value of d sub b is going to be
d sub b 的旧值或到达 a 的成本中的最小值
the minimum of the old value of d
sub b or the cost to get to a
d sub a 加上从 a 到 b 的直接成本
d sub a plus the direct cost to get from
a to b
同样，这里的逻辑是我们要将成本更新为 b
again the logic here is that we want to
update the cost to b
很清楚它不能超过 b 的旧成本
knowing well it can't be more than the
old cost to b
但现在我们知道 a 的最低成本并且我们知道
but now we know the minimum cost to a
and we know
从 a 到 b 的直接成本，所以我们想把这两个加在一起
the direct cost from a to b so we want
to add those two together
这会给我们带来 b 的成本
and that would give us the cost to b
going through
a 我们将取这两个值中的最小值
a and we're going to take the minimum of
those two values
所以你可以看到这里显示为灰色，我们更新了 d sub v 的值
so you can see here shown in gray we
update the values of d sub v
d sub w 和 d sub y 以及你可以看到 dw 的新成本
d sub w and d sub y
and as you can see the new cost for dw
和 dy 现在更少了，到达 w 的成本从 5 降到了 4 并且
and dy are now less the cost to get to w
has gone down from five to four and the
到达 y 的成本已经从无穷大下降到
cost to get to y
has gone down from infinity now down to
两个所以我们要更新这些值
two
so we're going to update those values in
上表，然后迭代回到开头
the table above
and then iterate back to the beginning
现在我们已经完成了循环中的两行
of the loop
well now we've completed two rows in the
表，我们又回到了循环的开始
table and we're back at the beginning of
the loop again
所以我们在识别步骤让我们找到节点 a
so we're at the identification step
let's find the node a
这还不是具有最小值 d 的 n 素数
that's not yet an n prime that has a
minimum value of d
sub a 看上面的表格我们可以看到
sub a looking at the table above we can
see
节点 y 的成本为 2，节点 v 的成本也为 2。我们可以
that node y which has a cost of 2
and node v also has a cost of 2. we can
随意打破这种关系让我们选择 y 所以我们将添加
break that tie
arbitrarily let's choose y so we'll add
y 进入集合 n 素数现在我们继续给定的更新步骤
y into the set n prime
now we move on to the update step given
我们已将 y 添加到素数中，这是第 11 步。
that we've added
y into a prime this is step 11.
我们想要在这里再次做的是我们想要更新 d sub b
what we want to do again here is we want
to update d sub b
对于在这种情况下与 y 相邻的所有 b
for all b that are adjacent to y in this
case
还没有在 n 素数你看到更新公式here
and not yet in n prime you see the
update formula here
好吧，让我们来看看为什么我们刚刚添加了 y
well let's take a look at why we just
added y in
并且 y 有两个尚未加入的邻居
and y has two neighbors that are not yet
in  prime that's w and z
n 是 w 和 z 的素数，所以我们要更新 w 的值
n prime that's w and z
so we're going to update the values of w and z as shown here
和 z 如此处所示，您可以看到
w 的新成本现在从 4 减少到 3 并且
and you can see that the new cost to w is now decreased from
到达 z 的新成本从无穷大减少到 4。
four to three and the new cost to get to z has decreased from
所以我们更新了上面的表格，我们准备再次迭代
infinity to 4. so we update the table above and we're ready to iterate
好吧，我们第三次在第 8 步再次进入循环，我们再次
again well we're entering the loop again at step 8 for the third time
从识别步骤开始，让我们找到不在 n 质数中的节点 a
and again we start with an identification step let's find the node a that's
然而，这样 d sub a 是最小值，因为我们
not in n prime yet such that d sub a is a minimum and
扫描我们在步骤 2 中计算的行
as we scan across the row that we computed in step 2 we see
我们看到 v 现在是最小值，代价是 2。
that v is now a minimum at a cost
we see that v is now a minimum at a cost
我们看到 v 现在是最小值，代价是 2。
of 2. so let's add v into the set and prime now that we've
既然我们已经完成了识别，那么让我们将 v 添加到集合和素数中
下一步将再次成为更新步骤
done the identification step the next step is going to be the update step
现在我们要更新与这个新节点相邻的所有节点的 d sub b
again and now we want to update d sub b for all nodes that
我们刚刚添加到 n 个素数中的节点 v 你看到了
are adjacent to this new node v that we just added into n prime
那里的更新公式让我们看看这里的节点 v
you see the update formula there let's take a look at node v down
我们刚刚添加了哪些邻居不是
here that we just added in well what are the neighbors that are not
然而在直接连接到 v 的 n 个素数中
yet in n prime that are directly attached to v well use in it
很好地使用它已经 x 已经在它里面但是
already x is in it already but
use in it already x is in it already but
w 不在其中，因此我们按照此处的步骤中所示更新 w
w is not in it so we update w as shown in the step
以灰色显示，我们看到 w 的成本没有改变
here shown in gray and we see that the cost to w hasn't changed
所以我们都完成了更新步骤让我们再次循环
so we're all done with the update step
let's loop back again
一旦我们再次进入循环，我们首先进行识别
and once we enter the loop again we
first do the identification
让我们找到一个不在 n 个素数中的节点，使得 d sub a 是最小值
let's find a node not in n prime such
that d sub a is a minimum
好吧，只剩下两个节点不在 n 质数中
well there's only two nodes left that
aren't in n prime
w 和 zw 的成本是三，而不是 z 的成本是四
w and z w has the smaller cost of three
rather than z's cost of four
所以我们要把 w 添加到 n 个素数中 我们要执行一个
so we're going to add w into n prime
we're going to perform an
再次更新步骤您可以很好地看到更新步骤是唯一一个节点
update step once again you can see the
update step well the only node whose
成本需要更新是 z 所以你看到更新的步骤
cost needs to be updated
is z so you see the step for updating
z 的成本 d sub z 的值不变
the cost of z
the value of d sub z doesn't change so
表保持不变，我们再次循环返回
the table
remains the same we loop back again to
第八步 进入识别步骤，我们将
step eight
enter the identification step and we'll
找到一个不在 n 质数中的节点 a 使得 d sub a 是 a
find a node a
not in n prime such that d sub a is a
最小井只剩下一个节点是 z 所以我们将添加 z 和素数
minimum well there's only one node left
that's z so we'll add z and and prime
现在没有节点了，所以没有更新步骤
and now there are no nodes left so
there's no update step
我们退出算法，我们都完成了，现在如果你看一下
we exit the algorithm and we're all done
and now if you take a look at the
在左下角的网络中，您可以看到成本最低的路由树
network in the bottom left hand side
you can see the least cost routing tree
从节点 u 到网络中的所有其他节点
from node u
to all other nodes in the network from
这样我们就可以恢复转发
this
we're able to recover the forwarding
如果我们想到达目的地，请专门从您那里获得
table specifically
from u if we want to get to destination
v 我们在这里浏览此链接
v
we go across this link here with a
2 的直接成本，否则如果我们想从 x 到 y
direct cost of 2
otherwise if we want to get to x to y
到 w 或到 z 我们将把一个数据包转发到 x
to w or to z we're going to forward a
packet to x
因为 x 是成本最低的下一跳节点
because x is the next hop node on the
least cost
从 u 到所有目的地 xyw 和 z 的路径
path from u to all of the destinations
x y w and z
好吧，我希望关于 dijkstra 算法的讨论给了你一个
well i hope that discussion of
dijkstra's algorithm has given you a
关于集中式链路状态算法如何工作的好主意，让我们
good idea of how a centralized
link state algorithm works and let's
在这里结束我们对 dijkstra 算法的讨论
wrap up our discussion here of
dijkstra's algorithm with a discussion
它的复杂性 它的计算复杂性 它的信息
of its complexity
its computational complexity its message
复杂性以及现在要考虑的可能病理的讨论
complexity as well as a discussion
of a possible pathology now to think
关于计算复杂性注意我们需要通过
about the computational complexity
note that we need to pass through that
从第 6 行到第 11 行循环 n 次，每次我们去
loop from lines
6 through 11 n times and each time we go
通过那个循环，我们必须制造更坏的情况
through that loop we have to make a
worse case
在比较中，这会给我们一个订单 n
in comparisons so that will give us an
order n
平方计算复杂度让我们分析一下消息的复杂度
squared computational complexity
let's analyze the message complexity of
从dijkstra的算法来看
dijkstra's algorithm from the point of
view
传播链路状态信息所需的消息数量
the number of messages needed to
disseminate link state information
每个路由器需要向n个其他路由器广播它的链路状态信息
each router needs to broadcast its link
state information to n other routers
还有广播算法真的很有趣
and there are broadcast algorithms which
are really pretty interesting
只需要n个链接交叉点即可传播
that only require of n link crossings to
disseminate
从一个源到 n 个其他节点的广播消息，回忆现在有
a broadcast message from one source to n
other nodes recalling that there are now
在源中，整体消息复杂度为
in sources
the overall message complexity to
因此传播链接状态是 n 阶平方
disseminate link state
is therefore order n squared
在结束我们对链接状态算法的讨论之前
and before wrapping up our discussion of
the link state algorithm
让我们考虑一个可能出现的非常有趣的病理
let's consider a really interesting
pathology that can arise
我们还没有对链接成本说太多，但现在想象一下，链接成本是
we haven't said much about link costs
but imagine now that link costs are
动态反映链接上的负载量
dynamic
reflecting the amount of load on a link
例如，负载越高，一些最早的成本就越高
for example the higher the load
the higher the cost some of the earliest
arpanet 中的路由算法仅使用这种短期
routing algorithms in the arpanet
use just this kind of short-term
负载相关的链接成本我们将看看下面的例子
load-dependent link costs
we'll take a look at the example below
链路成本等于负载的简单网络拓扑结构
of simple network topology
where link costs are equal to the load
继续链接注意现在的成本不同
carried on the link
note that the costs are now different in
链接上的每个方向让我们假设节点 bc 和 d 每个
each direction on a link
let's assume that nodes b c and d each
只想将流量路由到节点 a 和 b 并且 d 发送一个单元
want to route traffic
only to node a and b and d send a unit
发往 a 和 c 的负载发送少量负载
of load destined to a
and c sends a small amount of load
epsilon 到 a 并假设初始路由为
epsilon to a
and suppose the initial routing is as
链接状态算法下次运行时显示在最左侧
shown here on the far left
when the link state algorithm's next run
节点 c 基于链路负载和它们的第四个成本确定
node c determines based on the link
loads and their fourth costs
现在到 a 的逆时针路径的成本为 1
that the counterclockwise path to a now
has a cost of 1
而应该一直使用的 a 的逆时针路径
while the counterclockwise path to a
which should have been using
成本为 1 加 2 epsilon 现在 c 到 a 的最低成本路径是顺时针
has a cost of 1 plus 2 epsilon now
c's least cost path to a is clockwise
类似地，b 确定它到 a 的新的最低成本路径
similarly b determines that its new
least cost path to a
也是顺时针方向，导致第二个图中所示的路由
is also clockwise resulting in the
routing shown in the second figure
当链路状态算法的下一次运行节点 bc 和 d
when the link state algorithm's next run
nodes b c and d
现在都检测到逆时针方向的零成本路径，并且
all detect now a zero cost path to a
in the counterclockwise direction and
所有人都将他们的交通路由到逆时针路线
all route their traffic to the
counterclockwise routes
下次算法运行 bc 和 d 时，顺时针方向的成本都为零
the next time the algorithms run bc and  all see zero costs for clockwise
d all see zero costs for clockwise
路由因此顺时针路由他们的流量
routing therefore route their traffic clockwise and so on well this was just a
等等，这只是一个玩具场景，但它
反映了动态路由算法可能非常微妙的事实
toy scenario but it reflects the fact that dynamic routing algorithms can be very
可能正是因为这些问题，后来的路由算法
subtle and it was perhaps because of such issues that later routing algorithms tended
倾向于回避基于短期的成本定义
to shy away from defining costs based on short-term congestion or load levels well
拥塞或负载水平很好地结束了我们对
dijkstra 的集中式链路状态路由算法
that wraps up our discussion of dijkstra's centralized link state routing algorithm but we're
但我们还没有完成路由算法，因为接下来
not done with routing algorithms yet because coming up next we're going to take
我们将看看一种非常不同的算法
a look at a very different kind of algorithm  take a look at a distributed bellman  ford routing algorithm
看一看分布式bellman Ford路由算法 [音乐] 你
[Music]  you